Profile (Dr.M.IYAPPARAJA)

Name	Dr. M.IYAPPARAJA
	Associate Professor,
	School of information Technology,
	VIT, Vellore – 632014
	TAMILNADU, INDIA.
Education	B.E(CSE),M.E(CSE),PhD(ICE)
Contact	
Phone :	9942532920, 7904046040
Email:	iyapparaja85@gmail.com, iyapparaja.m@vit.ac.in

BIO

Dr. M.IYAPPARAJA is an Associate Professor in School of Information Technology and Engineering, VIT, Vellore. He was previously worked as an Assistant Professor in K.S.R College of Engineering (Autonomous), Tiruchengode (2008 – 2014) and Lecturer in Bangalore college of Engineering and Technology, Bangalore (2007-2008). He completed his Ph.D. Degree in the area of "Risk Assessment in Software Engineering" from Anna University, Chennai. He has 11 years of teaching experience. He has published more than 30 papers in Scopus and SCI impact factor journals and conference proceedings. His areas of research include Software Engineering, Big data, Cloud computing and Software Testing. He produced one Ph.D. (Information technology) candidate in the area of Big data in cloud computing in VIT, Vellore during 2018. He completed one consultancy project during 2013-14. Currently he is guiding three research scholars in the area of software testing, big data and IoT. He received gold medallist award for attaining university rank in PG level. He received Best Young Researcher National Award in the year 2018.

SUB HEADINGS

1. Academic Appointments
Associate Professor

2. Administrative Appointments

(Mention the administrative designation if any appointment order is received from the University)

- NAAC Coordinator from June 2018 to till date
- Anti-Ragging coordinator during the year 2018-19.
- M.Tech (CCE) Year coordinator during 2018.
- SET Conference coordinator during May 2015.
- NAAC core committee member in University level from May 2015 to June 2016.
- ABET committee member during 2015 16.
- 3. Honours and Awards
- Received Best Research Cash & Certificate award in VIT University from 2015 to till now.
- Received Gold Medal for University Rank holder in M.E(CSE).
- Best Young Researcher National Award 2018
- 4. Boards, Advisory Committees

Life member - ISTE (LM74411) ,2011 onwards

5. Current Research and Scholarly Interests

Software Testing, Big data in cloud computing

6. 2017-18 Courses

Software Testing

Software Project Management

OOAD

Object oriented programming

7. VIT Advisees

Names of Ph.D Advisees

- 1. Mr.Gopalakrishnan
- 2. Mr.Devaarul
- 3. Mr.Sathishkumar mani
- 8. Publications (List of all publications till date including journal and conference)

International Journal

- M. Sathishkumar, M.Iyapparaja, A Queuing Theory Model for E-Health Cloud Applicatio International Journal of Internet Technology and Secured Transactions. (In press)
- M.lyapparaja, et.al., Proposed Variants of Charged System Search Algorithm for Location And Optimization in Mobile Wireless Communication Networks, International Journal of Compunication Aided Engineering and Technology Inder science (In Press).

- 3. M. Sathishkumar, **M.Iyapparaja**, A Review on Utilizing Queueing Models for Improv Performance in Cloud, Jour of Advanced Research in Dynamical & Control Systems, Ap 2018,14(10),pp.1730-1741.
- S. Deva arul, M.lyapparaja, Social Internet of Things Using Big Data Analytics and Secur Aspects – A Review, accepted for publication in Service Oriented Computing and Application (SOCA), Springer (IF: 0.921).
- 5. C.Gopalkrishnan, M.Iyapparaja, Active Contour with modified Otsu method for Automa Detection of Polycystic Ovary Syndrome from Ultrasound Image of Ovary, accepted publication in Journal of Multimedia Tools and Applications, Springer (IF: 1.579).
- 6. **M. lyapparaja**, Dr.P.Sivakumar, Case Study: Detecting Diabetic retinopathy exudates in dig image processing hybrid methodology, accepted for publishing in Research journal of pharma and technology, Jan 2019,12(1), DOI: 10.5958/0974-360X.2019.00011.8, pp:57-61.
- 7. **M.Iyapparaja.** et. al., Proposed variants of charged system search algorithm for location at optimization in mobile wireless communication networks, accepted for publishing in I Journal of Computer Aided Engineering and Technology (Inderscience).
- 8. **M. Iyapparaja.** et al., Case Study on Big Data Inspection in Pharmaceutical Services, Jour Advanced Research in Dynamical & Control Systems, April 2018,10(5),pp.1558-1561.
- 9. **M. Iyapparaja.** et al., The Sequence Way of Performance Analysis for Device to Dev Communication, Jour of Advanced Research in Dynamical & Control Systems, At 2018,10(5),pp.1562-1570.
- 10. **M. Iyapparaja.** et al., Diagnosing Sudden and Gradual Drifts in Business Process, Jour Advanced Research in Dynamical & Control Systems, April 2018,10(5),pp.1583-1589.
- 11. **M. Iyapparaja.** et al., Maching Language Prediction Algorithm for Crypto Currency, Jour Advanced Research in Dynamical & Control Systems, April 2018,10(5),pp.1576-1582.
- 12. **M. Iyapparaja.** et al., Arranging Job Flow on Hadoop, Jour of Advanced Research in Dynami & Control Systems, April 2018,10(5),pp.1571-1575.
- 13. **M. lyapparaja**, Dr.P.Sivakumar, Metrics based evaluation for disease affection in distinct citi Research journal of pharmacy and technology, Oct2017,10(8),pp.2487-2491.
- 14. **M. Iyapparaja**, C. Navaneethan, S. Meenatchi, P.J. Kumar, P. Suganya, A Privacy-Preserv Secure Access Control Mechanism in Cloud, Jour of Adv Research in Dynamical & Cont Systems, Aug 2017, 12, pp. 844-850.

- 15. **M. Iyapparaja**, C. Navaneethan,S. Meenatchi,Pthanapal, Prabhakar, Ciphertext-Scheme Bas on Attribute Hybrid Encryption in Cloud Computing, Jour of Adv Research in Dynamical Control Systems,Sep2017,13, pp.309-317.
- M. Iyapparaja, C. Navaneethan,S. Meenatchi,Pthanapal, Prabhakar, Network Life Til Uniformed by Mutual Nodes Cooperation and Life Nodes Relay in WSN's, Jour of Adv Reseatin Dynamical & Control Systems,Sep 2017,13,pp.144-148.
- 17. **M. Iyapparaja**, C. Navaneethan,S. Meenatchi,P.J. Kumar,P. Suganya, Secured Sharing Data Cloud Using Revocable Storage Identity Based Encryption,Jour of Adv Research in Dynamica Control Systems, Sep2017,13,pp.318-326.
- 18. **M. Iyapparaja**, C. Navaneethan,S. Meenatchi,P.J. Kumar,P. Suganya, Two Lay 'Red Optimiz System Using Bluetooth and HipherLAN Interfaced Wireless Sensor Networks, Jour of A Research in Dynamical & Control Systems, Sep 2017, 13,pp.327-330.
- 19. **M. Iyapparaja**, C. Navaneethan,T.T. Vihar, P.thanapal, K.N.S. Kartheek, A New Algorithm Password Encryption and Decryption,Jour of Adv Research in Dynamical & Cont Systems,Sep2017,13,pp.246-251.
- M. Iyapparaja, C. Navaneethan, R. Saranya, Pthanapal, S. Meenatchi, Techiecardia-A System
 Detection and Prediction of Sudden Cardiac Arrests, Jour of Adv Research in Dynamical
 Control Systems, Sep2017,13, pp.339-344
- 21. **Iyapparaja, M** 2016, 'Coupling and Cohesion Range Metric Measurement for Identifying Disease Pattern of Pharmacy Medical Data', International Journal of Pharma and Biosciences (Scorlindexed) journal.Sp.02 "Healthcare Technology and Management", pp. 44-47, (SJR=0.39, 5.121).
- 22. **Iyapparaja, M** 2016, 'Coupling and Cohesion Metrics Based Measurement of Software Reusa Component Strength', International Journal of Pharmacy and Technology (Scopus Indexe journal, vol.8, no.4, pp.21515-21526.
- 23. **Iyapparaja, M** & Sureshkumar, S 2015, 'Intelligent Risk Analysis Model for Mining Adapta Reusable Component', International Arab Journal of Information Technology **ELSEVIER**, v 12, no.6A, pp.680-687, **(Impact Factor 0.582).**
- 24. **Iyapparaja, M** & Kishorekumar, A 2015, 'An Improved Face Tracking Method in Wireless Sen. Networks for Effective Recognition of Target Node', International Journal of Appl Engineering Research, vol.10, no.2, pp. 3889-3897, (Impact Factor 0.166).

- 25. **Iyapparaja, M** & Sureshkumar, S 2015, 'Normal Distribution and Questionnaire Bas Assessment of Risk in Software Reusability', Australian Journal of Basic and Applied Science vol. 9, no.11, pp.160-166, (Impact Factor 0.472).
- 26. **Iyapparaja, M** & Sureshkumar, S 2015, 'Rank based Reusability and Risk Assessment (RRF Model for software component Reusability', International Journal of Applied Engineer Research, vol. 10, no.38, pp.28618-28623, (Impact Factor 0.166).
- 27. **Iyapparaja, M** & Sureshkumar, S 2015, 'An Ample Survey of Risk Analysis in Software Reusal Components', Global Journal of Engineering Science and Research, vol.2, no.4, pp.1-6.
- 28. **Iyapparaja, M** & Sureshkumar, S 2013, 'A Concise Survey of Risk Management in Software Reusable Components', International Journal of Innovative Research in Computer a Communication Engineering, vol.1, no.9, pp. 2151-2155.
- 29. **Iyapparaja, M** & Sureshkumar, S 2012, 'Test the Excellence of Module set Interactions in Objoriented Software System', International Journal of Advanced Research in Technology, vol. no. 3, pp. 52-58.
- 30. **Iyapparaja, M** & Sureshkumar, S 2012, 'Extreme Confidential Component Mining Based Coupling and Cohesion Strategy in Cloud Computing', International Journal of Advance Research in Computer Science and Software Engineering, vol.12, no pp.315-320, Impact Factor 2.080.

Paper Published in Refereed Conference

International Conference

- Iyapparaja M., Singaravel G., and Geetha B.G., (2010), 'Inheritance Related Risk Coding Factors of Agile Method in IRRF Tool', IEEE International Conference on Innovative Computing Technologies (ICICT 2010), held at M.Kumarasamy College of Engineering, Karur, pp. 23-33.
- 2. **Iyapparaja M.,** (2011), 'Analysis of Professional Risk Management for Software Quality Assurance', **3rd International conference on computing and communication technologies** (N3CT-2011), held at Surya Engineering College, Erode, pp. 35 42.
- 3. **Iyapparaja M.**,(2012), 'Test the excellence of module set interactions in object oriented software system', **International conference on (ICACT 2012)** held on J.K.K. NATTRAJA college of engineering and technology, Tamilnadu, india.
- 4. **Iyapparaja M.,**(2012), 'A succinct survey of reusable packages in software engineering', **International convention cum pre conference workshop on "Innovations in Engineeing and technology for sustainable development** held on Bannari amman Institute of technology & University of Derby.

- 5. **Iyapparaja M.,**(2012), 'Analysis of risk Analysis models', in **International conference organized by the department of computer applications** in Dr.M.G.R. University & Educational and research Institute, Chennai.
- 6. **Iyapparaja M.,** (2012), 'Coupling and cohesion metrics in java for adaptive reusability risk reduction', presented in **IET(UK) International Conference on 'sustainable energy and intelligent systems (SEISCON)** organized by Vivekanadha college of technology for women & IET(UK), Tiruchengode.
- 7. **Iyapparaja M.,** (2019), 'Detection of polycystic ovary syndrome from ultrasound images using SIFT descriptors', presented in Second International conference on Information and computational Intelligence (ICICS-2019) in K.S.R. College of Engineering, Tiruchengode.
- 8. **Iyapparaja M.,** (2019), 'Hybridization approach to classify Big data using social IoT', presented in Second International conference on Information and computational Intelligence (ICICS-2019) in K.S.R. College of Engineering, Tiruchengode.
- 9. **Iyapparaja M.,** (2019), 'A Survey on analysis of chronic diseases prediction in Big health care data using IoT', presented in Second International conference on Information and computational Intelligence (ICICS-2019) in K.S.R. College of Engineering, Tiruchengode.

National Conference

- 1. **Iyapparaja M.,** and GaneshKumar k.,(2009), 'Overview Analysis of Organizational and Professional Risk Management for Software Security Project', **National Conference on Current Trends in Computer Science and Information Technology (NCCTCSIT'09)**, held at Paavai Engineering College., Namakkal, pp. 27-36.
- Iyapparaja M., (2011), 'Coupling based structural metrics for testing module set interactions in an object oriented software system', Seventh National Conference on recent trends in advanced computing held at SNS College of technology, Coimbatore. Pp. 135 – 139.

9. Others

- **Keynote speaker** of International conference on computational and Engineering technology, 27th and 28th March 2018, K.S.R.College of Engineeing.
- **Keynote Speaker & Technical session judge** in 3rd Two days National Level Conference on Recent Innovation, Engineering, and Technology & Management 2017 held in Priyadarshini Engineering College, Vaniyambadi on 07-04-2017.
- **Guest Lecture** for Anna University sponsored FDP Programme at Information Technology Department, K.S.R College of Engineering, Tiruchengode.
- **Jury** for National Level Technical Symposium (MAHOTSAV 2013) at Computer Science and Engineering Department, K.S.Rangasamy Institute of Technology, Tiruchengode.
- International Conference Chair at MCA Department, K.S.R. College of Engineering, Tiruchengode
- Chaired a session at the National Level Technical Symposium "ABLAZE 10", Department of Computer Science and Engineering held at K.S.R. College of Engineering, Tiruchengode on 24.02.2010.